C=[{
            "question_number":1,
            "question": "An exception is __",
            "options": ["Runtime error","Compile time error","Logical error","None of the above"],
            "answer": "Runtime error"
},

{
            "question_number":2,
            "question": "Where to place “f” with a double constant 3.14 to specify it as a float?",
            "options": ["(float)(3.14)(f)","(f)(3.14)","3.14f","f(3.14)"],
            "answer": "3.14f"
},

{
            "question_number":3,
            "question": "Which library function can convert an unsigned long to a string?",
            "options": ["ltoa() ","ultoa()","system() ","unsigned long can’t be converted to a string"],
            "answer": "ultoa()"
},

{
            "question_number":4,
            "question": " Which files will get closed through the fclose() in the following program?
                        #include<stdio.h>

                        int main ()
                        {
                        FILE *fs, *ft, *fp;

                        fp = fopen('ABC', 'r');
                        fs = fopen('ACD', 'r');
                        ft = fopen('ADF', 'r');
                        fclose(fp, fs, ft);
                        return 0;
                        }",
            "options": ["ABC","ACD","ADF","Return error"],
            "answer": "Return error"
},

{
            "question_number":5,
            "question": "What is the output of the below code snippet?
            #include<stdio.h>

            main()
            {
             int a = 5, b = 3, c = 4;
             printf(\"a=%d,b=%d\n\",a,b,c)",
            "options": [" a=5, b=3","a=5, b=3, c=0","a=5, b=3, 0","compile error"],
            "answer": "a=5, b=3"
},

{
            "question_number":6,
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?
            #include<stdio.h>

              main()
              {
                 printf(\"""\");
              }",
            "options": ["\"","","\"","Compile error"],
            "answer": "Compile error"
},

{
            "question_number":7,
            "question": "To print a double value which format specifier can be used?",
            "options": ["%L","%lf","%Lf","None of the above"],
            "answer": "%L"
},

{
            "question_number":8,
            "question":"Choose the correct order of evaluation",
            "options": ["Relational Arithematic Logical Assignment","Arithmetic Relational Logical Assignment","Logical Arithmetic Relational Assignment","Assignment Arithmetic Logical Relational"],
            "answer": "Arithmetic Relational Logical Assignment"
},

{
            "question_number":9,
            "question": "Which header file supports the functions - malloc() and calloc()?",
            "options": ["stdlib.h","memory.h","math.h","stdio.h"],
            "answer": "memory.h"
},

{
            "question_number":10,
            "question": "The maximum combined length of the command-line arguments as well as the spaces between adjacent arguments is – a) 120 characters, b) 56 characters, c) Vary from one OS to another",
            "options": ["a","a, b","a, b, c","c"],
            "answer": "c"
},
{
  "question_number":11,
  "question":"What do you mean by int (*ptr)[10]",
  "options":["ptr is an array of pointers to 10 integers","ptr is a pointer to an array of 10 integers","ptr is an array of 10 integers","Invalid statement"],
  "answer":"ptr is a pointer to an array of 10 integers"
},
{
  "question_number":12,
  "question":"In the given below statement, what does the “pf” indicate? int (*pf)();",
  "options":["pf is a pointer of a function which return int","pf is a pointer","pf is a function pointer","None of the above"],
  "answer":"pf is a pointer of a function which return int"
},
{
  "question_number":13,
  "question":"A Variable name in C includes which special symbols?",
  "options":["* (asterisk)","# (Hash)","+ (Addition)","_ (underscore)"],
  "answer":"_ (underscore)"
},
{
  "question_number":14,
  "question":"#include<stdio.h>

  main()
  { 
     int *p = 15; 
     printf('%d',*p);
  }",
  "options":["15","Garbage value","Runtime error","Compiler error"],
  "answer":"Runtime error"
},
{
  "question_number":15,
  "question":"#include<stdio.h>

  int* f() 
  {
     int x = 5;
     
     return &x;
  }	
  main() 
  {
     printf('%d', *f());
  }",
  "options":["5","Address of ‘x’","Compile error","Runtime error"],
  "answer":"Runtime error"
},
{
  "question_number":16,
  "question":"#include<stdio.h>

  main() 
  {
     unsigned x = 5, y=&x, *p = y+0; 
  
     printf('%u',*p);
  }",
  "options":["Address of x","Address of y","Address of p","5"],
  "answer":"5"
},
{
  "question_number":17,
  "question":"#include<stdio.h>

  main()
  { 
     int x = 3;
     
     x += 2;
     x =+ 2;
     printf('%d', x); 
  }",
  "options":["2","5","7","compile error"],
  "answer":"2"
},
{
  "question_number":18,
  "question":"#include<stdio.h>

  main() 
  { 
     char s[]='hello', t[]='hello';
     
     if(s==t){
       printf('eqaul strings');
    }
  }",
  "options":[" Equal strings","Unequal strings","No output","No output"],
  "answer":"No output"
},
{
  "question_number":19,
  "question":"#include<stdio.h>

  void f(int a[])
  {  
     int i;
     
     for(i=0; i<3; i++)
        a[i]++;
  }
  main()
  {	
     int i,a[] = {10, 20, 30};
     
     f(a);
     for(i=0; i<3; ++i)
     {
        printf('%d ',a[i]);
     }
  }",
  "options":["10 20 30","11 21 31","Compile error","Runtime error"],
  "answer":"11 21 31"
},
{
  "question_number":20,
  "question":"Which of the following statement shows the correct implementation of nested conditional operation by finding greatest number out of three numbers?",
  "options":["max = a>b ? a>c?a:c:b>c?b:c","a=b ? c=30;","a>b : c=30 : c=40;","return (a>b)?(a:b) ?a:c:b"],
  "answer":"max = a>b ? a>c?a:c:b>c?b:c"
}
]
